yeah welcome back everyone thank you for
being on time um yeah and Welcome to our
afternoon sessions we have four
interesting talks um the first one is
about the challenge of finding and
retrieving unstructured information and
interesting challenge uh I've also
struggled with myself so really looking
forward to this talk uh Joe Christian uh
from WBA I think probably needs no
introduction uh search
veteran uh is talking about how Vision
language models help with that task and
he is introducing kly P to us I'm right
stage is yours thank you very
much yeah first of all it's great to
being here at hyack again it's a really
great conference really high signal to
noise rate show uh I'll talk about a
topic that I'm very excited about um and
the pitch is what you see is what you
search and using visual language models
for PDF retrieval I do believe that this
is um the kind of future uh of
retrieval um but in this deck I'll talk
about
introduction uh indexing and searching
PDFs talk about Vision language models
VMS kpali I don't know so how many of
you heard about C poly before uh tra
talk this morning couple of hands good
so you will learn about colp
today um and scaling
colp rag of course retrieval augment
generation using vlms and then QA and
resources and also um if you want to
jump to the deck um you can scan
that so
how many of you have tried to index
PDFs quite a few okay so this is I think
it's quite
um it's quite amusing I think Charlie I
asked him if he could do the intro on
how difficult this but he said I would
use all your time so we're not doing
that uh but PDFs can be quite complex uh
they can contain like visual
infographics tables shock s
images and at the start of the chat GPT
rag wave Vector database chat with your
PDFs whatnot uh actually chatting with
the PDFs was one of the kind of primary
hello world use cases um because there's
real value in that because a lot of
information in the world is buried in
these
PDFs
and to do that you need some kind of
extraction because you you want to map
it to text at least that's what we used
to do and then you have to trunking text
embedding and
whatnot um but
extracting text out of these documents
is is quite
messy um it's maybe not so visible here
but this entire element of this
PDF uh is not extractable because it's
an embeded
image so you can clearly see there's
text there's numbers
here and if you do this by text
extraction and your manager is trying
the new search interface and he's
searching for something that is present
in this
information uh it's it's not going to be
retrievable you won't be able to find
this document right and this can be very
hard to explain to people that are not
used to uh technology right I it I can
see the text there why can't your search
engine retrieve it right it it sucks
when you yeah but it's a embeddable
image what do you mean by embeddable
image is the text is there I can clearly
see it right and you go like yeah but uh
not only that uh so then you turn to
some text extraction routine um and on
the right side here I actually display
the text if you're using a popular way
to extract text uh you can see the
headline sustainability and nature has
become nature
sustainability one word right which then
makes basically both those two words
unretrievable because in a regular
lexical Tech search system right it
would be indexed as one token so if
someone searched for nature it would not
be retrievable right so it's it's
messy and in in addition ordering as
well you can see that the first chunk of
text is we manage biodiversity risks and
mitigate impacts which actually is all
the way down here right that's the first
Chunk in the text
extract so it's it's it's
messy but why do we extract the text in
the first place why do we try to move
this kind of complex format and and
convert it into the text domain well of
course we need to convert it to
something that makes it searchable and
we need to have it in text because we're
going to use something to search it with
and historically we would use AP pase
solar or elastic search or open search
or Lucine or Vasa or something or we
would use like a fancy embedding model
chunking whatnot but we would have to
extract it to text and there are a lot
of companies around or Technologies as
well aposta is a welln technology for
extracting text out of a wide range of
document formats it's it's great um
llama Cloud also that's the Llama index
people they also went into this route
and so okay we're going to build our
business model around extracting data
out of complex
documents and unstructured also get your
data rag ready y yti uh Tesseract is uh
one of the most popular OCR Frameworks
lot of
complexity and
then we will talk about Vision language
models so how many of you have tried uh
chat GPT or gptt 4 with the vision
capabilities have you like tried
uploading an image asking questions
about it okay so quite a few that's
good so what is a vision language model
uh broadly these are multimodel models
that can learn from both image and text
at the same time so on the top here uh
here's the VM there's a text input
there's an image and the model generates
some text um
and these are typically generative
models all the demos are around cats uh
you can ask a question uploads some
image of a cat what is the breed of
these cats and you get response and this
is my view of VMS been for quite some
time that you use it for searching cats
uh to find cute cats on the internet and
I made this overview and we are
unfortunately very soon in 2025 this
year flew by uh this is an inaccurate
summary of the VM landscape uh we didn't
have very powerful VMS at the start of
this year so at the start of this year
VMS searching cats not so interesting um
then we got some powerful models from
open AI then there's been a bunch of
models and I made this uh
diagram on Wednesday last week and just
after that there were
two new uh powerful Vision language
models released uh Mulo from ai2 and
llama
3.2 from meta and it turns out that this
can do more
than just uh searching from text or
searching for cats I
mean so polygama is one of these aition
language models that came out earlier
this year and was released with um open
weight so you can use it under certain
terms it's not a open source per
definition uh
model but it came with uh it was trained
on multiple different
tasks uh and one interesting aspect of
it was that it had pretty strong what we
call OCR capabilities or the ability to
read text from an
image this as enables it to do question
answering so on the right side here I
have uploaded um the PDF page or a
screenshot of the PDF
page um and this part is not extractable
because it's embedded image and I'm
asking what is the percentage of
produced water that is
reused and it answers
4.56% which is uh in this green bottom
here is 45.6% of produced water is
reused or uh recycled
that that's quite powerful right that
you can
actually answer a question like this
given one image of a PDF right so that's
actually real uh progress of what you
can do with these type of
models and uh here's an
example uh with a different open source
open open weight open source model from
Quinn uh this was released I think four
weeks ago and and uh for fun I uploaded
an image from our Vasa performance
dashboard and asked it you know what's
in the image
and uh I could basically use this to
explain to managers at westa what are we
actually looking at uh because it it so
accurately describes what's in this
photo uh it includes it says that the
there's performance test here there
different versions of the software
labeled as XY y set which is the version
on the x-axis it understands that the
latency on on y- axis is latency It also
says that the blue lines bits bits
Hamming shows a significant decrease in
latency from version blah blah blah to
uh and indicating improved performance
so it's quite astonishing that it can
actually take a screenshot explain to me
what's going on here right uh I know
there are a lot of like executive
dashboards graphs charts whatever you
can just enter the VM I will summarize
it for you so
um and these insights into the actual
power of these
vlms uh made the researchers behind colp
to see can we actually use these VMS for
uh
retrieval and what do I mean by
retrieval right so in the previous
example we basically gave the model
here's the screenshot here's the
question okay so you could do that uh if
you have a collection of let's say
100,000 images you could kind of ask
more model for one image of a time and
then ask to you know score them right
but it would be quite time consuming
because these models are quite big they
have High
lency um so kpali the idea behind kpali
is to use the capabilities of these
VMS and extend that capability for
document retrieval so let's say we have
100,000 PDFs we want to search across
them efficiently
and they also argue that in the
Practical industrial
settings um we don't have the luxury as
well of pre-processed data sets right so
when you talk about you see numbers here
ngcd from Ms Marco and so forth but
there we are looking at clean
pre-processed Text data sets right we
have the passages they're clean nicely
formated and everything we have the
queries they are nicely formated and we
measure ngcd we measure sh in we all
kinds of stuff we look at the mtab
leaderboard Benchmark right but in the
industry when you want to take PDFs and
make them searchable it's quite messy
it's it's quicker that that actually is
the bottleneck of your performance end
to end than whatever embedding model
you're using right as you saw that the
text extracted was not really well
done um and that's what they're trying
to achieve with Kali I'm not associated
with any of these but when I saw this
paper in July this year I was like oh my
God this is huge um and I've ever since
then actually invented a lot of time in
it uh on the top here this is a diagram
from uh the original paper where they
kind of outlin their method and I'm not
going to spend too much time on this but
they argue that a regular retrieval
pipeline for PDFs would include text
extraction OCR layout detection then
chunking embedding and whatnot uh while
they replace reping all of that
complexity with a single model that
takes the the screenshot of the page as
an
input and col poly is actually short for
col
polyma so col polygamma is the visual
language model
backbone and Co is from a concept called
contextualized embeddings over so and we
will get into that what that means but
um Cal is these multiv Vector embeddings
directly from the screenshot of the PDF
page or a text query and is using this
visual language model as the
backbone and then at the scoring time
similar as you're doing a bm25 score or
a multiv vector score or a single Vector
score there's some interaction between
these text Square vectors and the
embeddings that you get from the
screenshot
and thankfully Trey gave a great talk
this earlier and talked about buy
encoders cross encoders a lot of
different name so here it is it's a Bion
coder architecture because the
architecture that you're suggesting
enables this offline indexing so you can
take all the pages you have and then you
can process them produce embeddings by
them and when a user shows up at query
time we can do the matching okay instead
of having to input both the page and the
query at the same time into the model
which is more of the Cross encoder model
that Tre talked
about and what's the what's the benefit
well you can have matching without text
extraction so you can score documents in
the collection without having to go
through the text extraction steps you
can avoid OCR you can avoid layout
detection to identify figures or tables
you just embed the
screenshot um simple approach
engineering wise you don't have to have
a very complex document processing
pipeline also as we will see it also has
a better relevancy when we compare it
with more traditional methods and I
believe it's a future direction for
document
retrieval um essentially because can you
print the document means that you can
actually index it with the c po approach
so it's more Universal for different
types of file formats than ever before
because it's the same kind of Technology
when we are sending something to the
printer right we're essentially sending
a image
right and now it gets harder so you have
to focus
um
uh so using this page uh and the page is
actually divided into a a grid of 32 *
32 what they call
patches and as essentially one image is
wor thousand words we say something like
that in in Norwegian at least I don't
know if it translate to English but in
reality with this VM one image is worth
words and um each of these patches
though I didn't draw all of them because
my drawing skills are not so good but
each of them are represented as a as a
vector representation so 128 dimensional
vector and we can call this like the
latent
Vector space where we project uh all
these images into so that you have a lot
of the vectors for each of these
cells at the same time it's also
matching text um and you can because you
the model access both text and the image
at the same time and the Cali
architecture they prefix the input with
like describe this
image um because they didn't want to do
any kind of text extraction in theory
you could actually extract text like if
you're doing e-commerce search you have
the product title you have the product
description you could actually input
both representation at the same time so
when you're querying in text you could
actually attend to both the product
description and the image um so there's
a lot more potential uh in this um and
it deals with page level representation
right so it doesn't embed the whole PDF
document so maybe you have a PDF
document of thousands of Pages it
obtains one representation per page and
in the Vasa language uh you can
represent this as a pet as a tensor and
it basically is a tensor which has one
map Dimension here called patch and V
128 stands for um Vector of 128
Dimensions you can see this as a if
you're familiar with the map data
structure uh there's a map where the key
is the patch and the vector is the value
so this is the what uh representations
that you obtain on the document
side same on the query side you're
mapping uh queries into embedding
vectors and you have an embedding Vector
per query token or word um these
language models they basically tokenized
text so what is the percentage of
produced water that is reused will be
tokenized into predefined token in the
in the language model and each of those
are represented as
embedding uh and each of tokens has a
vector representation here so you have
basically a token level embedding
representation and
then you have a similarity phase uh
between these two so when you want to
score a document or a page for a query
you have this kind of interaction uh
between this and this interaction is
called the sum of Maximum similar
arities also called late interaction I
will explain this in more detail in the
next slide and this is where the name is
from so call PO is essentially
contextualized late interaction over
embeddings from
polyma you
can replace polygama with a different VM
right so you can have call Llama 2 or co
uh Quant 2 as we will see but
so you can't actually replace that but
we'll get to that so what is the
maxim um you essentially compute a
similarity
Matrix uh after between all the query
tokens and all the patch tokens on the
image so I try to illustrate this here
uh where I've divided the page into just
four cells okay so and each of these
cells are represented here in my example
as a two-dimensional Vector in reality
in Cali is 128 Dimensions right so I
have four
cells so and you have two query tokens
uh so water and recycle and each of them
are represented as a vector then you
take the representation for water and
you calculate the dot product against
this cell this cell this cell this cell
and you find the maximum in this case
it's this cell so the example is made up
okay for illustrative purposes same with
r recycle um 36 this one is the best
matching and the final
score for this page for this query is 74
is is that clear is
it but in reality right you have a lot
more of these patches uh there are
higher Dimensions
128 uh but that's the idea of this Maxim
similar for text for Colbert which is
the text version of this
um you basically just have text and text
uh on both ends here but for polygam p
sorry for call P you are um kind of
meeting the image representation and the
text representation inside this latent
Vector space
okay and then of course if you can
express this type of scoring uh how do
you find the most relevant documents
well you compute this score for all the
documents and then you sort them by this
score so this is just what we do with
bm25 right and the scoring function is
very similar actually to to bm25 which
also a sum of
something um but how do you go
from uh
polygamma that's been trained on a lot
of different tasks for question
answering and whatnot
to obtain representations that are good
for retrieval right so I cannot really
take the base model and then chop off
this layer and chop off this layer and
obtain some random vectors here and
there and then say oh there there
there's your retrieval model that
doesn't work um so the way they do this
is that they add an adapter to the VM
and the VM is actually Frozen and Frozen
means that the weights here are not
adjusted during training they're they're
frozen because this is a rather large
model it's like two billion parameters
instead it had this small adapter that
they lay on top of the
model and we want to learn
representations so that these tensil
representations and the maxim scoring so
that it ranks these relevant U documents
above those that are not relevant and
the way you do that is that you have
this kind of triplet data you have a
text query you have the image of a page
that is deemed to be relevant and you
have an example of a page that is not
relevant right so this is crucial for
getting a good representation out of
this right without this step it's going
to produce uh verse results than random
okay you have to have this kind of Step
um and here's the big block of relevancy
training
data so this is the same thing with uh
when the embedding model providers they
train models right they invest in this
and how to train uh models but they take
some kind of pre-train model and then
they adapt it for retrieval if it's a
single Vector text embedding model as
well similar thing then they have a lot
of tricks like the guys here from from
mix bread to make this really work
really well um but this step is
crucial and this is representational
learning learning representations that
are useful for
retrieval so um how does colpal compare
with other traditional
methods uh they released also with the
paper uh a benchmark called The Vi
Benchmark which is because the issue is
that with the current benchmarks you're
dealing with clean text clean data right
so they compare here with um here's
actually an overview of what's in the
data sets um not a lot of documents
actually but still different tasks and
I've highlighted some areas here uh
where archive X questions or these ones
uh
bm25 text extraction methods you cannot
extract text from these documents so so
they they are blank you have to add OCR
in order to get something and here they
also have of course the bm25 Baseline
pretty good Baseline actually uh um NGC
d565 and doing embedding retrieval yeah
a little bit better uh but
CP U is significantly better and also
interestingly enough even on the domains
here um where bm25 works
well and uh embedding also works well so
these are text Heavy documents not not
that many figures or infographics or
whatnot right even there compile works
really well and the Simplicity comparing
to a system where you extract Shunk
whatnot
OCR uh and still compile it that is just
embedding the photo I think this is
quite
amazing uh yeah some samples from The
Benchmark to give you an idea of what's
actually in The Benchmark so there's a
wide range of document formats uh in The
Benchmark some are
scanned uh here's a table from some
Nursery home so it's actually quite
complex quite hard data
set and U of course of course we talked
about kopali there's a lot of vectors
here right there is one vector per patch
uh in the image there's one vector for
the query how can we scale this for
practical applications uh there are two
components here in scaling C PO for
production it's a storage and compute
okay and compute is more or less
quadratic with the number of query
tokens and the number of patch vectors H
and of course with the
dimensionality and the storage scales
with the number of documents times the
number of patches times the vector
diality uh and in this I don't actually
talk about like actual model inference
but you actually take the text input to
the model to to the inference right
that's a separate
thing um so there are a couple of
options you can do you can reduce the
patch vectors and you can look at the
vectors from a page and you also you saw
that in the in the screenshot of the
page there are a lot of white areas
right they're not very meaningful so if
you take all the vectors you can red you
can remove the Redundant vectors right
those that measure the same information
and by doing this uh you reduce the
number of vectors P so this reduces the
both the storage and the compute
complexity then you can also reduce the
position so instead of using float which
uses five bytes per value you can use uh
one bit instead and then you can replace
uh float dot product with uh Hamming for
example this is the same kind of
learnings we've had from uh binary
quantization uh the guys from mixed
bread train they're embedding models for
quantisation um great way of reducing
cost uh so this reduce storage by 32x
and compute by by 4X
plus you can do uh a phe retrieval and
ranking where you use hnsw or nearest
neighbor search to First you take those
query token vectors do a search for all
of them and then you rerank using Maxim
and then you can use uh a different
granularity and top here on one of the
benchmarks float float resolution gives
you ND cd5 at 52 and you can pretty much
uh retain the accuracy just by using
binary representations
so I yeah I spent last three months on
Kali so I've written three blog posts
about it so but the to Long didn't read
is to reduce reduce the pr
Precision uh and to use binary
quantization replace the dot product
with Hamming and then use H&S W indexing
of these patch
vectors rag uh of
course uh it's important today uh lots
of model that accepts uh rather large
context window now so you can actually
input a lot of data to them uh colp is
the first stage right of such a system
when you're are retrieving uh data for a
rag pipeline you actually input the
images uh that are retrieved from uh
kpali and then you feed them into the
generative model and the amazing thing
is that uh this Benchmark this mm long
Benchmark which was just accepted I
think to NP shows that um when you give
the model screenshots of the pages the
accuracy is better for gp4 than when
you're using OCR plus text so even the
generative models works really well with
uh with these type of source of
information um so does it work for my
data of course so I'm more in to the
direction using VMS because it solv so
much many problems but there is a model
checkpoint out there that the researcher
trained right but that's just one model
checkpoint in time right how can I adapt
this to my
data uh you can find un it uh someone
even made like a a hug in face space
where you can explore this upload uh
photos and then have a generative model
actually uh generate synthetic questions
that would match this so this would B
form you would do this not in this UI
you would do this systematically you
will take your documents you will have
the model uh create questions and this
will create your relevancy data set to
Pine tune C po so that your checkpoint
is better than the kind of one that you
can find on hug in face right
now uh can't you use gp4 for this uh I
always get get this question uh you can
uh if you can fit all of your documents
into the context window and you can wait
for 30 seconds uh it works reasonably
well so copal is about uh doing an
efficient uh
retrieval and on Friday the authors also
released a new checkpoint that is now
based on a different totally open source
model and this increases the ngtd by
Five Points so it's even better than the
previous checkpoints and I predict that
we will see more checkpoints we will see
embedding providers as well going into
this direction because it's such a
attractive Direction where you don't
have to do text extraction for retrieval
so I I'm um I am a huge believer in this
direction uh yeah and I have a lot of
resources uh on this and uh I don't
understand why my timeline is not all
about copal because it's it's really
it's really a fantastic uh way of of
building search in this complex format
so and more we we created a lot of
notebooks and how to use it inesta and
so forth so and I really recommend to
play with Vamps for different tasks
entity extraction whatnot uh try them
out so yeah then I can take your
questions
thank you very much for the inspiring
talk we have one question online that
relates to retrieval of tabular data so
the question is how does
copal keep the context of tabular data
so if you have a table a large table
that has some headings and you have the
small 32 by 32 image patches how is it
able to keep that context even over a
longer table
yeah so this is more of a let me see so
this is the kind of data that uh is part
of the Bor Benchmark right so you
essentially all of these are just
divided into grids and based on the
quality of the training data uh that you
use to train the Cali model the
checkpoint right that's that's that's
how this work right so the model is not
better than what it was trained on but
the initial pre-training step of the VM
gives it these kind of OCR capabilities
right reading text and that's what we
are exploiting here with this adapter so
but I can't answer like specific you
know how the hell can it actually read
this and how the hell can it actually
explain what I saw here with the
performance Benchmark right that's a
little bit magic as well okay
thanks questions
thanks for the great talk Joe thanks um
you mentioned one of the techniques to
possibly reduce the number of vectors
that you can do is for example look for
sparse uh or white space kind of patches
yeah uh and remove those vectors so I'm
wondering is this you know the output of
col po or or polyma is uh is it High
Fidelity compared to this kind of you
know how many pixels are different
colors can I can I do this thresholding
after I compute the vectors or do I have
to do something else yeah that's a great
question so uh regardless of the how the
footo uh how the footo actually looks
the the output eddings are you get 1030
vectors out so the the clustering
approach you use is a post inference
stage so it doesn't have to retrain the
model in any way you basically take the
vectors and then you look at the vectors
and say I'm going to remove the ones
that are very similar right because they
don't give you any value and there are
going to be a lot of vectors that are
very similar because they're just
encoding a blank space in this and um a
team of resourcers demonstrated that
both for Co p and Colbert you could
reduce uh the number of vectors by 3x
without having a very significant impact
on the ngg so yeah
okay the online community has a question
uh or rather two question about uh
language specific fine-tuning one is if
there if you're aware of a data set for
fine tuning for example for the Spanish
language um and the other is um yeah do
you are you aware of any fine tunes for
any other languages like Norwegian
German Etc y so uh the Cal paper
actually evaluates the model was trained
purely on English data uh they do
evaluate it on a French test set that is
part of this so the the
initial uh snapshot has multilingual
capabilities right so the the text model
that is part of uh polygama actually has
multilingual capabilities but in order
to have it shine on your language on
your type of documents this step is
required
right uh so no I'm not familiar with any
kind of checkpoints so I'm here more to
talk about the direction like we moving
in a direction where you can use the VM
as the backbone instead of just using a
text encoder uh there will be
checkpoints uh there's going to be a lot
more checkpoints uh I think in the
coming coming months so yeah have you
seen any interesting approaches to
handling contextualizing information
being split across different
pages uh yeah the the first blog post
post that I did about Kali really like I
really want to flex all the thing we
have in wesa uh but I I took it too
far uh and where I demonstrated that hey
you can take one PDF uh put it into Vasa
it's just a tensor with another
dimension which is the page and then you
can do a maxim calculation across all
these pages and all sorts of things and
people like oh what the hell is this you
know too difficult so I had to dumb it
down and one page is one bestel document
but when you ret if you want to return
like what's the most relevant document
like you're not in a rag setting but you
you most L document then you can do like
grouping aggregation on top of this and
then Group by relevancy and and like
what's the best matching Pages within
the document yeah so but uh the first
blog post I did is like uh yeah if
you're into it then you can read
it but I was so excited because it
dropped I had a few days of vacation
actually and this dropped and I was like
what the hell I have to demonstrate this
with a notebook and I was like why are
you working on the weekend like with
this yeah but this is so exciting so I'm
yeah and uh I wondering how practical is
to use kpali in the real life so how
much time does it take to do inference
of like a Gemma to produce uh 1,000
embeddings per page yes very good uh so
if we talk about uh there um two things
here one is the cost of inference of the
polygam model on the document side on my
laptop here it's a M1 uh it takes 2.5
seconds uh on this M1 no no the MPS
encoding uh encoding the query
takes uh I think less than 100
milliseconds on on M1 uh for
maxim uh it depends
on uh a couple of fiber parameters like
hnsw like you're retrieving with
multiple qu vectors and then the ranking
of Maxim but the benefit of Westar in in
this case is that you're not moving
vectors around to the network so you can
move vectors into the CPU at the speed
of memory bandwidth right because if you
see someone say oh we support Maxim in
Colbert but the way you they do this is
that they first do a nearest neighbor
search and then petch all the vectors to
perform the maxim uh then watch your
network uh
footprint uh it doesn't scale
yeah okay got another online question
that's actually also would have been my
question uh let's say I have a less
complex PDF which is mostly text yeah
perfectly extractable yeah will call
Pell still work and have a performance
lead over something similar like
Colbert um yeah this is a great question
uh we can go back
[Music]
to so if if I have text
um so these these subsets are text heavy
and bm25 works well uh regular embedding
model with chunking also works well uh C
is slightly better I think if you change
the Baseline here with something like
Colbert uh which is just text domain uh
it will Bridge the the the the
difference and if you go with sea and
talk to him about his mono T5
ranker it's probably going to be maybe
even better yeah so if you're text Heavy
you have your extraction routine you
don't have to start uh taking
screenshots of things to embed them with
C poly yeah so and if you have your data
already structured in your data base
okay you don't have to take a screenshot
of it and embed it with C but I'm I'm
talking about complex documents here
HTML msword whatnot right uh that's the
type of use case you want to explore
this but I do see that this will play a
role in e-commerce search because you
can take the structured product title
the product description and the image
representation and have a joint
representation of this and then at C
time you have your text tokens so you're
attending to both the product text and
the photo at the same time clip is also
used for this but it only encodes like
uh either the text or the image so you
have to do some kind of model and add
things on top of this to make it joint
just
works it will work more
questions Hey Joe thanks for the talk um
a question about explainability yeah it
strikes me that actually if you got the
page and you're breaking the page up and
you're using the max Sim presumably
there is a way of reverse engineering
that so you can then say these bits to
the page of the things that that are
most relevant for the query yeah that's
that's a great question Alan so uh I'm
not sure if it if it shows here but they
actually demonstrate this in the paper
uh the interpret
interpretability or explainability it's
easier to say explainability of the
model is that you can since the maxim
scoring really you find the max patch
for this query Vector so you can kind of
highlight it in the image uh so you can
figure out from all of the text tokens
you know where are they actually scoring
in the document so they have some nice
infographics around this uh we also did
a demo of this in the text domain
Colbert with text where you can actually
highlight uh the text on the query why
is it scoring like this and that's
that's a huge benefit over uh single
Vector models right because you
basically just take all the patches and
then into one vector representation but
you have no idea why this document is
ranking uh in in this way
so
yeah okay one more question
I don't want to be a fire starter but
how many search engines in this room can
do this kind of multi Vector late
interaction uh thing I I you know like
uh to so to you know build on your
question uh on Twitter you know why is
the you know your Twitter empty of
talking about kpali uh yeah it's it's a
question I know uh engines that can do
multiv Vector
representations uh there are quite a few
uh
there are pros and cons but I know that
uh quadrant has support for multiv
Vector
representations uh I think Lance DB has
support for multiv Vector
representations and of course uh vesa
with our tensor
framework uh I think the Lucine based
engines uh don't have support for it
because they rely on Lucine I know that
there are some tickets and issues around
it so might happen um
and also I think you can probably hack
around it also with PG Vector in some
cases but not with combined with hnsw
indexing
so I think that's a
fairly accurate summary so thank you we
are at time so we have more questions
online my suggestion would be to just
maybe contact Joel yes you find me on
Twitter uh just shout out me there I'm
I'm there so all right so yeah fill up
his timeline and thank you Jo